Hsaine El-Ali

Address: Traubenweg 1,

4123 Allschwil, Switzerland.

Telephone: +41 76 341 61 97
E-Mail: <u>elalihsaine@gmail.com</u>

Birth date: 23.06.1993

Nationality: Canadian, (Swiss Permit C)



Summary

With 2 years of consulting experience in **life science**, and skills in programming (**Python, C**), **Artificial Intelligence**, and **Agile Software development (CSPO)** techniques. Knowledge of the software market. Currently doing my master's in medical informatics.

Professional experience

Feb 2022 - Present

CTC Resourcing Solutions

Consultant life sciences

At CTC I am responsible to recruit for IT and preclinical development.

- Develop and execute fully strategic sourcing plans to build talent pools in advance of our client hiring needs
- Hunt passive candidates from all over Europe through online networking and referrals
- Write compelling job descriptions and advertise them on multiple online platforms
- Pre-screen of high volume of resumes and conduct qualification calls
- Use diligently applicant tracking and sourcing tools
- Generate Talent Insights reports, to understand talent supply and demand
- Generating Business Inteligence about the industry through candidates relationships
- Editing of candidates' resumes
- Prepare and coaching candidates for interviews via teams or in person
- Present top candidates to Account manager and Client with all required and accurate information
- Complete required references checks
- Facilitate offer negotiations and acceptance
- Facilitate candidate onboarding
- Organize team activities and quarterly company off-sites

Mar 2020 – Sep 2021

Aerotek, part of Allegis Group (now Actalent)

Recruiter in life science IT

- Full life cycle of the recruitment process
- Organizing and conducting meeting with stakeholders

Main profiles in IT: Software Engineers, Software Architects, IT Project Manager, Cloud professionals.

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

KPMG

Administrative assistant

- Responsible for administrative tasks in GMS (Global Mobility Service) tax department
- Compiled client's tax dossiers and submitted them to respective governmental or cantonal authorities
- Handling of sensitive documents

Sep 2018 – Jan 2019

Albrecht Catering AG (Student job)

Logistical assistant/Event management (part time, student job)

- Responsible for the logistics of large catering events
- Inventory assessment and management

Sep 2015 – Sep 2018

Swiss International School (Basel)

Logistical operator/Teacher assistant (student job)

- Facility management
- Responsible for the Sports club

July 2015 – Aug 2015

Hotel chain DOM, Saas-Fee, Switzerland

Section supervisor

- Interacted and served clients
- Managed Inventory, and placed orders when needed
- Section accounting

July 2014 – Aug 2014

La Salinas Scuba Diving Center, Enfeh Lebanon

Customer support manager

- Greeted clients and walked them through safety guidelines
- Oversaw equipment logistics and maintenance

June 2012 - Aug 2013

Systema Comfort, Moscow Russia

Associate key account manager

- Responsible for 10 client accounts
- Repurchasing and delivery of goods based on customer needs and account specifications

Education

Sep 2021 – Dec 2023

Master's in Medical Informatics (part-time)

Fachhochschule Nordwestschweiz, Muttenz

• Specific application of modern digital techniques to software development and artificial intelligence methods applied to healthcare

Sep 2014 - June 2020

Bachelor's in Business Administration

Fachhochschule Nordwestschweiz, Olten

- Exchange semester: HAN University, Netherlands
- Major: International Entrepreneurship
- Minor: Financial risk management
- Bachelor's thesis: "Pricing analysis for ASPIVIX SA", Financial live project (score 6),
- Research paper: "Blockchain and supply chains"

• Charity event manager (as part of exchange semester)
Sep 2011 – Jun 2012 Medical studies

University of Liege, Belgium

Jun 2011 French Baccalauréat/Scientific

Lycée Jeanne D'Arc, Mulhouse, France

Certifications:

2022 Certified Scrum Product Owner

Languages:

English/French: FluentGerman: B2Arabic: A2

Russian Native

Computer skills:

Microsoft office: Excel, Word, PowerPoint, Outlook,

Internet Skills: Academic research

Outlook: Very good

• Systems: SAP, LinkedIn recruiter, Weka, Tableau, Jira

Programming
 Python, HTML, Artificial intelligence algorithms

Interests:

• Outdoor sports (diving, sailing, skiing), Brazilian Jiu-Jitsu, Reading